Nikhil Gunti

314 N Duncan St, Apt 6, Stillwater, OK

□ 405-762-0337 | ■ nikhil.gunti@okstate.edu | • nikhilgunti | • □ gunti-nikhil/

Professional Summary _

Business acumen with 3+ years of experience in product development domain having hands-on SQL, Python, R, and other technologies. Strong working knowledge performing statistical data analysis & models using Pandas, Numpy, Scikit and developing Tableau dashboards.

Education

Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, OK

CGPA: 4.0

MASTERS IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS & DATA SCIENCE

Aug. 2019 - May. 2021

JNTUH College of Engineering, Hyderabad, India

CGPA: 3.5

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug. 2013 - May. 2017

Technical Skills & Certifications

- Programming Languages: C/C++, SAS, SQL, R, Python, Matlab, Verilog
- Tools: Alteryx, R Studio, Tableau, JMP, Power BI, Postgre SQL, Visual Studio, Frameworks: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch
- Certifications: Computer Vision NanoDegree Udacity, NLP, Deep Learning Specialization Coursera, SAS Programming Certified
- Scholarships: National Science Foundation(NSF) I-Corps CIE Scholar 2020

Work Experience

Concat Systems Dallas, TX

DATA SCIENCE INTERN May. 2020 - Present

- Implemented various object detection algorithms and trying to integrate DeepSORT algorithm to detect 20 custom objects in a video
- · Worked on OpenCV CSRT/MOSSE trackers to track a custom scratch/dent on cars 360' videos for several car dealers

Computer Science Department - OSU

Stillwater, OK

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May. 2020 - Present

- · Associated with Professor Dr. Sathyanarayanan Aakur on Computer Vision research Independent Study
- Working on research project to understand visual world beyond recognition or captions without the need for explicit human supervision through expensive annotations by developing self-supervised predictive learning for video event segmentation

Wipro Limited Hyderabad, India

PRODUCT ENGINEER Aug. 2017 - Jul. 2019

- **Data Analytics** Ran Naive Bayes & logistic regression models for multi-class text classification based on case description. Also, analyzed the factors behind lease cases and tried to predict the number of lease issues for next quarter.
- $\bullet \ \ \textbf{Consulting -} Assisted \ clients \ with \ both \ functional \ \& \ technical \ issues \ of \ the \ product \ TRIRIGA, \ specifically \ lease \ accounting \ of \ product \ accounting \ of \ accounting \ of \ product \ accounting \ of \ accounting$
- Case Resolution Debugged platform & application issues of product and resolved 234 client cases in a year (2nd in team of 19)
- **Team Management** Promoted to team lead and entrusted with responsibility to manage a team of 3 experienced professionals

Publications.

- Accepted paper "Benchmark and Evaluation of Low Resource Object Detection in Biomedical Images" at AIPR 2020
- Submitted "Knowledge Guided Learning: Moving towards Open Domain Egocentric Action Recognition with Zero Supervision"-AAAI '20

Academic Projects

Fault Diagnosis in steel plates using Machine Learning

OSU

Feb. 2020 - Apr. 2020

Executed feature selection using PCA to identify variables involving pattern recognition and fault classification in steel plates

Performed comparative analysis of Machine learning models to derive important variables in determining faults beforehand, thereby
optimizing product testing cost & enhancing production quality

MetroTech Center Retention OSU

DATA ANALYST

DATA ANALYST

Aug. 2019 - Nov. 2019

- Identified a list of factors contributing to overall student satisfaction(pattern) by analyzing 5 yrs of student survey responses. Interesting correlations between the variables influencing retention rate were drawn for further analysis
- Built various ML models & interactive dashboards to analyze the drop-out pattern and provided strong recommendations

Customer Feedback Analysis of Apple Products

OSU

Data Analyst Sept. 2019 - Nov. 20

 Scraped data from Twitter & other social media websites and performed web content mining to analyze user's feedback on recently launched Apple iPhones. Used libraries like NLTK, Gensim to perform sentiment analysis & named entity of customer reviews

Leadership & Management Roles

- **President:** My role as President for Business Analytics Student Association(BASA) includes organizing technical workshops by industry leaders, meetups/fun-activities, ensuring cultural diversity, assisting BASA members for internship/job opportunities
- **Community Development Volunteer:** Worked with 'YouthForSeva' to stabilize the financial status of impoverished kids in public schools by enabling them to bag scholarships and conducted career empowerment sessions & weekend classes on maths and science